have you guys ever heard of the birthday
Paradox imagine a group of 23 random
people what is the probability that at
least two people have the same birthday
and these are random people so no Twins
or anything like that so it's going to
be easiest to calculate the probability
that nobody has the same birthday and
then just do 100 minus whatever that
gives us first let's start with one pair
of people so the first person has a
birthday whatever that is then what is
the probability that the second person
does not have the same birthday well
there are 364 possible days that don't
match out of 365. so their probability
is 364 over 365. now let's bring in a
third person what is the probability
that that third person does not have the
same birthday as either of those other
two well that leaves 363 out of 365 days
so we can just multiply these and the
fourth person to not match any of these
three would be 362 over 365. and this
pattern continues for the rest of the
people in the group after we multiply
all of these probabilities we get
approximately 49.27 so the probability
is 49.27 that no one shares a birthday
so if we do a hundred percent minus that
we get a 50.73 probability that at least
two people have the same birthday so if
it feels weird that 23 people out of 365
days can do this it might be better to
look at this the number of pairs if we
look at the first person in the group he
has 22 pairs you can match with then the
next person has 21 new pairs they could
match with and the next person has 20
new pairs of people they can match with
and this pattern is going to continue so
there are going to be 253 pairs we're
just trying to get at least one of these
253 pairs to match and if you think of
it that way the 50.73 seems much more
realistic every one of these 253 pairs
is a possible chance for a birthday
match and this is the birthday paradox